## Michael Kelly Web Front End/Ruby Developer

## Who am I?

Contact Info

I am an Expert Software Engineer with two decades of experience designing and building software in the intelligence community. I love to make web applications that are polished, standards based, and user friendly. While I prefer to work on the front end, my Computer Science background lends well when I need to get my hands dirty on the back end of systems. These skills have played a large part in the launches of 8 major web applications, four of them flagship level.

Michael Kelly michael.i.kelly@gmail.com (mailto:michael.i.kelly@gmail.com Ashburn,VA USA

## Experience

## Expert Software Engineer, ByteRatio, Reston, VA (2019-Present)

Developer Lead for a web application providing search capabilities for a large datastore using Angular 11. Responsible for mentoring junior team members and ensuring best practices are followed. (2021-present)

Front End Team Lead for a flagship web application delivering timely information for worldwide customers using Angular 8. Responsible for mentoring junior developers on the team in best practices. (2020-2021)

UI Team Lead responsible for modernizing legacy Angular/Node password management application using React. Architected repeatable deploy process using Docker and AWS. (2019-2020)

#### Skills and tools used:

HTML, CSS, React JS, Angular 8,11, NodeJS, Git, Docker, and AWS.

## Expert Software Engineer, Excivity, Inc, Chantilly, VA (2017-2019)

Web UI Team Lead responsible for growing junior developers on team.

Designed, Architected, and built Single Page Application (SPA) for User Communications (both text based and real-time voice with historical playback), and User Management of system

Architected and built SPA for management and interactive use (via VNC within a web page) of Android Mobile Device Emulators running in a cloud-based environment.

Researched and developed automatic build pipeline using Docker and Gitlab for release management.

#### Skills and tools used:

HTML, CSS, React JS, WebRTC, JavaScript, Photoshop, Git, Jira, Docker, and GitLab.

## Owner and Developer, URL Droplet, Ashburn, VA (2011-2018)

Designed and developed web application for downloading files to a Dropbox account with just a URL. URL Droplet has been featured on Lifehacker (http://lifehacker.com/5811317/url-droplet-downloads-files-from-a-web-address-straight-to-your-dropbox), CNET (http://howto.cnet.com/8301-11310\_39-20073094-285/4-killer-dropbox-tricks/), and many other news sites and blogs around the world.

#### Skills and tools used:

Git, Photoshop, HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and MongoDB.

## Senior Software Engineer, GSM Consulting, Reston, VA (2012-2017)

Designed and developed a Ruby on Rails replacement for a Lotus Notes database. Transformed workflow to save 30+ man-hours/week. (2013-2017)

User Interface Design Team Lead responsible for branding and design of user experience. Consultant on multiple projects at client location. (2012-2013)

#### Skills and tools used:

Ruby on Rails, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Ember, React JS, JavaScript, Photoshop, and Git.

### Senior Software Engineer, NCI Inc, Reston, VA (2008-2012)

Lead Designer and Lead Developer for senior policy leadership's flagship publication web application using HTML/CSS/JS (JQuery) and Ruby on Rails. (2011-2012)

User Experience Designer for new search capability on flagship publication web application. Conducted User interviews, created prototypes and developed beta implementation. (2011)

Lead Designer and Developer for a streaming video web application using HTML/CSS/JS (Prototype) and Ruby on Rails. (2010)

Co-designed, and implemented a complete rebranding of client's flagship publication web application using HTML/CSS/JS (Prototype) and Ruby on Rails. (2009)

Developer for a publication web application using HTML/CSS/JS (Prototype) and Ruby on Rails. Responsible for designing admin tools and pages on the site using extensive use of AJAX. (2008)

#### Skills and tools used:

Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Prototype, Backbone, JavaScript, Photoshop, Oracle, and Git.

## Lead Software Engineer, SpecTal Consultants, Reston, VA (2006-2007)

Led and managed software development team that included three separate subcontractors designing and building a multi-modal biometric software system.

Responsible for planning the development schedule as well as keeping the team on schedule and on budget.

#### Skills and tools used:

Microsoft Project, Java, J2EE, HTML, CSS, and Subversion.

## Senior Software Engineer, L-3 Communications Titan Group, Reston, VA (2005-2006)

Led the User Interface team for a large scale Internet exploitation tool working on designs for the Graphical User Interface and integrated vendor components.

Designed and developed a Java Eclipse Plug-in for search within a knowledge management tool.

Designed and developed Java infrastructure applications to integrate a message feed into the overall architecture.

### Skills and tools used:

Java

# Senior Software Engineer, L-3 Communications Titan Group, Reston, VA (2004-2005)

Gathered customer requirements from the customer.

Designed and developed a business workflow processing system using Tibco.

Designed and developed Java remote execution and status display applications using JMS.

### Skills and tools used:

Java, JMS, and Tibco.

## Software Engineer, L-3 Communications Titan Group, Reston, VA (2002-2004)

Developed subsystems for XML message processing and correlation using C++ and Java.

#### Skills and tools used:

C++, Java, XML, CVS, and CMMI Level 3.

## Intern, Integrity Applications Inc, Chantilly, VA (2001-2001)

Implemented a browser-based graphical analysis subsystem driven by XML data using JavaScript, VBScript, XSL, and HTML.

#### Skills and tools used:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VBScript, XML, and XSL.

### Intern, Fairfax Imaging, Inc, Chantilly, VA (2000-2001)

Designed and implemented a graphical interface on top of an existing legacy application using C++ and MFC.

#### Skills and tools used:

C++, and MFC.

Clearance

Education

Active TS/SCI Clearance with Full Scope Polygraph

B.S, Computer Science, James Madison University (2002)